## DR. WAN SYASLIZA MOHAMED THANI

**DATE OF BIRTH:** January 16<sup>th</sup>, 1979

NATIONALITY: Malaysian

No. 20, Jalan Nusaputra 4/2C, Bandar Nusaputra, 47130 Puchong, Selango**r** 

EMAIL: wansyasliza@moh.gov.my

#### SUMMARY

Specialist in Special Needs Dentistry is involved in the dental management of patients with disabilities, provision of conscious sedation and dental treatment under general anaesthesia.

Over 15 years of experience in dental services including involvement in out-patient services, school dental services, community services, administration and attachment with specialists in other specialty.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- · Special needs dentistry
- Conscious sedation
- Dental treatment under general anaesthesia
- Rotary endodontics
- Simple and surgical extractions
- Crown and bridge work
- Removable prosthodontics
- Passion for continuous learning and personal growth

#### **SOFTWARE LITERACY**

Microsoft Office Applications

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

- Malaysian Dental Association
- Otago University Alumni

#### OTHER ACTIVITIES

- Represented Oral Surgery Dept. of Putrajaya Hospital for bowling tournament between Oral Surgery Dept. of Klang Valley 2010
- The Association of Wives and Women Staffs of Ministry of Health Malaysia (PUSPANITA)
  - lifetime member since 2004
- UKM Dental Faculty Alumni
  - member
- MARA Junior Science College Jasin batch 1995/96 Alumni
  - member

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

# **Doctor of Clinical Dentistry: Special Needs Dentistry** University of Otago

2015

New Zealand

The specialty involves:

- Dental management of individuals above 16 years old with special needs including geriatric patients.
- 2. Provision of conscious sedation techniques (inhalation, intravenous, intranasal and oral sedation).
- 3. Restorative dentistry with or without sedation which includes root canal treatment, removable denture provision, restorations, crown and bridge restorations, scaling and polishing.
- 4. Simple and surgical extractions with or without sedation.

- 5. Comprehensive dental treatment under general anaesthesia
- 6. Domiciliary dental care: A service provided to patients who cannot reach the dental service themselves due to severe disability. The dental treatment is carried out in patient's home where they are confined or in the hospital where they are admitted.
- Research title:

"Oral Candida Susceptibility and Antifungal Resistance in Individuals Taking Antipsychotic Medications"

## **Doctor of Dental Surgery (DDS)**

University Kebangsaan Malaysia

2003 Malaysia

Final Year Project (2002-2003):
 'Dental Ethics'

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### December 2016 - current

SEPCIAL NEEDS DENTISTRY UNIT, HOSPITAL RAJA PEREMPUAN ZAINAB II

(Dental Officer/ Clinical Dental Specialist UG54)

#### Involvement as:

- Head of Special Needs Dentistry services for Jabatan Kesihatan Negeri Kelantan (Department of Dental Health of the State of Kelantan)
- Head of Special Needs Dentistry Unit in Hospital Raja Perempuan Zainab II

#### **Continuing Professional Development activities:**

- Oral presentation titled "Oral Candida Susceptibility and Antifungal Resistance in Individuals Taking Antipsychotic Medications" during the National Oral Health Day, at Putrajaya International Convention Centre on 3 October 2018
- Organiser of "Hollistic Approach in Special Needs Dentistry Course" for dental officers in Kelantan held on 11 and 12 March 2019 at Hospital Raja Perempuan Zainab II
- Organiser of "Palliative Care in Dentistry for Dental Officers in Kelantan Course" on 18 April 2018 at Hospital Raja Perempuan Zainab II
- Organiser of "Introduction to Dentistry for Dental Officers in Kelantan Course" on 23 February 2017 at Hospital Raja Perempuan Zainab II
- Various talks given to dental officers in Kelantan and trainees, trainers and parents of trainees attending Community Based Rehabilitation Centres within the state of Kelantan

#### August 2015 - December 2016

SEPCIAL NEEDS DENTISTRY DEPT., KAJANG HOSPITAL

(Dental Officer/ Clinical Dental Specialist UG52)

#### Involvements:

- Taking responsibilities as the Head of Department of Special Needs Dentistry in Kajang Hospital
  - o Representing Dr. Siti Zaleha Hamzah (one year study leave)
- Quality Assurance Committee of Kajang Hospital
  - o Facilitator for dental specialties in Kajang Hospital

Head of "Code Blue" dental team of Kajang Hospital

#### **Continuing Professional Development activities:**

- Gave talk on "Behaviour management in special needs dentistry" to Dental Officers on 26 April 2016
- Author of article "Herbal Medicine in Dentistry: Should the Dentist Know?" for MyHealth portal
- Poster presentation titled "Oral Candida Susceptibility and Antifungal Resistance in Individuals Taking Antipsychotic Medications" during "16<sup>th</sup> International Association of Dental Research Malaysia Section Scientific Meeting", at Hotel Armada Petaling Jaya

#### **April 2009 - December 2011**

ORAL SURGERY DEPT., PUTRAJAYA HOSPITAL

(Dental Officer UG48)

#### Involvement as:

- Clinical Practice Guidelines of Putrajaya Hospital
  - Committee member since 2010
- In-charge person of Cone Beam x-ray machine in Department of Oral Surgery, Putrajaya Hospital since December 2010
- 9th Asian Congress Of Oral & Maxillofacial Surgery Pre Congress Workshop on "Implantology"
  - Committee member on 25<sup>th</sup> Nov. 2010
- "Management of Maxillofacial In-Patient" course, 5<sup>th</sup> till 7<sup>th</sup> Aug. 2009, Palm Garden Hotel, Putrajaya
  - Organizing committee

#### **Continuing Professional Development activities:**

- Gave talk on "Oral Cancer Awareness" to public during "Oral Cancer Awareness Week" at Department of Oral Surgery, Putrajaya Hospital held on 22<sup>nd</sup> Nov. till 25<sup>th</sup> Nov. 2010
- Gave talk on "Infectious Diseases" to Supporting Staffs (Dental Surgery Assistant and Attendants) on 17<sup>th</sup> June 2010 at Institut Pengurusan Kesihatan, Bangsar
- Poster presentation "Bisphosphonate Related Osteonecrosis of the Jaw: Our Management" in Research Day, Putrajaya Hospital, November 2011
  - o Third place winner

#### **Self Improvement:**

- Started attachment at Paediatric Dentistry Department of Serdang Hospital twice a month since January 2011
- Starting attachment with Special Needs Dentistry Registrar at Oral Surgery Department of Serdang Hospital twice a month since February 2011
- IELTS examination 2010 Band 8.0
- IELTS examination 2009 Band 7.0

### July 2005 - March 2009

SETAPAK GOVERNMENT DENTAL CLINIC

(Dental Officer UG41)

#### Involvement as:

- Committee of Occupational Safety and Health of Setapak Dental Clinic
  - Chairperson (2007-2009)

- Innovation Project 2007 Safety Base for Portable Light Cure Unit
  - Committee member
- Innovation Project 2008 Smart Clip for Patient's Bib and Sucker Tip
  - Committee member
- Community service for University Technology Malaysia's 2<sup>nd</sup> College open day 2008
  - Clinical service
- Power Point and Poster Presentation by Dental Nurses 2008, Setapak Dental Clinic
  - Tutor
- School Dental Program for Secondary School Setapak Dental Clinic 2008 -2009
  - Monitoring
- School for The Visually Impaired Setapak 2006-2009
  - Monitoring and yearly dental treatment
- Antenatal Program Setapak Dental Clinic 2008-2009
  - Monitoring

#### Giving talks:

- To Antenatal mothers, of Gombak Antenatal and Children Clinic
- Oral Health lectures to Form 4 and Form 2 students
- On "Oral Care for Children" lectures to pre-school and kindergarten teachers under The Association of Kindergarten Teacher and Manager
- On "Oral Care for Children" to parents of kindergarten children, Kindergarten at Block C of Taman Melati
- CDE presentation, at Setapak Dental Clinic
  - "Needle Stick Injury"

#### July 2004 - June 2005

CHINI DENTAL CLINIC, PAHANG

(Dental Officer U41 – Officer In-Charge)

#### Involvement as:

- Corporate Culture Incorporation, Pekan District level
  - Co-ordinator for dental division
- Community service for Rompin Village
  - Clinical service
- Community service for Indigenous people of Runchang Village
  - Clinical service
- Community service for Indigenous people, Muadzam Shah
  - Clinical service

#### Giving talks:

- One day seminar to dental staff of District of Pekan on "Ministry Of Health's Corporate Culture"
- To Antenatal mothers, Chini Polyclinic
- Oral Health lectures to Form 1 students
- 'Career in Dentistry' lecture to Form 4 students
- CDE presentation on 'Needle Stick Injury'

#### July 2003 - June 2004

**DISTRICT OF KUANTAN DENTAL CLINICS, PAHANG** 

(Dental Officer U41 – First Year Dental Officer)

Oral Surgery Clinic, Tg. Ampuan Afzan Hospital (Jul-Dis 2003)

Paediatric Dental Clinic, Tg. Ampuan Afzan Hospital (Jan-Feb 2004)

Main Dental Clinic, Jalan Gambut (Mac-May 2004)

#### Giving talks:

- To Antenatal mothers, Medical Clinic Jalan Gambut
- To high-risk caries secondary school students
- Lectures for training Dental Surgery Assistant (DSA)

#### Jalan Beserah Dental Clinic (June 2004)

• Setting up the clinic and became a temporary Officer In-Charge

#### **REFEREES**

Dr Rusli Bin Ismail
 Deputy Director of Health (Dental) of
 Kelantan State,
 Level 7, EPF Building,
 Jalan Padang Garong,
 15598 Kota Bharu, Kelantan
 Telephone No: +609-7443960

E-mail: dr.rusli@moh.gov.my
Position: Current employer

2) Associate Professor Dr. Tuti Ningseh Mohd. Dom Department of Dental Public Health

Dental Faculty,

Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Raja Muda Abdul Aziz, 50300 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Telephone No. : +603-92897731 Handphone No. : +6012-2861636

Fax No.: +603-26982944

E-mail: tutinin@gmail.com / tutinin@dental.ukm.my

Position : Former lecturer

3) Dr. Rohana Abu Kassim

Deputy Director of Health (Dental) of

Pahang State,

Panang State,
Pejabat Kesihatan Pergigian Negeri Pahang,
Tingkat 12, Wisma Persekutuan, Jalan Gambut,
25000 Kuantan, Pahang, Malaysia
Telephone No. : +609-4227291
Handphone No. : +6019-9354397 E-mail: damia\_60@yahoo.com Position : Former employer